Okay, so now in this video, we're going to add the first person controller package.
Right, we will not be creating a first person controller from the scratch we will be using
the package.
So what I'm going to do now is just double click on it.
And when you double click on the package, it will show this window.
Just simply click on import.
Then it will show this warning.
So I'm just going to click on install or upgrade.
And when it shows this window, just simply click on next and then click on import.
And now in a few seconds, our first person shooter will be imported.
But in between, if it shows this warning, you just have to click on less for these and
other files that may be found later.
As you can see right here, it is imported.
Let's create the console and everything is reloaded.
I think everything looks good as it was before right now.
Let's get back right here.
Okay, this is our whole environment.
In order to add the first person controller, there are two ways to write.
Actually, let me tell you this controller comes with two type of option.
Third person and first person, there are also the other type of perspective, but we just
going to ignore that right, we are making the first person shooter.
So let me tell you how you can add that.
If you click on third person controller right here, get this folder, then in the prefabs,
if you click on game, then character prefabs in here, you can find this first person character.
So you can just drag and drop it to the environment.
And you can then also go back and open up the camera, prefab and try and drop the first
person camera right there.
Right, when you do these two things, right, you can click on camera, right, it is set up.
You can then just go ahead and play the game and when the game starts, the player will
be in here because we didn't set up the player for this terrain.
So just stop the game, get back right here, right, this is the whole environment.
You can change its layer two, terrain, click on yes, change children, and then you can
also tag this as cross, right, since there is most of the cross area in this game.
So then you can go ahead and play the game again and when you play the game here, we are
now the player can walk around in the environment.
The player can do punches and the player can dodge the areas in the game as you can see.
And also the player can shoot, right, but we will not be using this controller, right,
this is just a method in which you can add the first person controller, right, I'm just
going to stop the game, clear out the console, right, and now I'm going to show you how you
can set up this whole thing.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to select both of these controller and delete it.
Then as you can see, this is the environment, what I'm going to do is in the assets, I'm
going to create a new folder by the name of game, as it's alright, and then insert this
game as it's I'm going to create one more folder by the name of pre-fabbs, and in this
pre-fabbs I'm going to try and drop this environment, right, once we have this environment,
then I'm going to click on third person controller folder, and then I'm going to click
on demo scene, and here I'm going to open up this FPS sample, right, this is the FPS
sample, what we're going to do now is, if you double click on the first person character,
here it is, alright, we'll be using this first person character, which is already fully
set up as you can see, alright, so what we're going to do is we're going to select all
of it and create empty parent for it, let me name this environment to be deleted, okay,
because from this, we're going to delete most of this stuff, so the first thing which
we will be deleting, if you click on game view, we're going to delete the screen controls,
okay, deleted, then you can open up the user interface, and from here, delete the inventory
and the load items, alright, we will leave the game manager, and the input manager,
there it is, let's check what is this, alright, this is the slow motion system, just
to say when that disabled is on this corner, disable the waypoint path, the pickable items,
then the salute character, that example, you can also disable the info trigger, the
petrol motorcycle car bike, reflection probe, you can leave the post processing volume as
it is, let's remove the physical cubes, the playground and the directional light, alright,
yep, disable that as well, and you can actually disable the post processing volume as
well, alright, then what we're going to do is we're going to select these three things
and let's move it outside and these two things as well, for now we're just going to
leave that as it is and select all of these, create empty parent, let's name this as
clear, it will be later, alright, okay, now if you click on game assets pre-fab, let's
drag and drop the whole environment in there, when you do that, okay, here we are, let's
get the plan now in the camera, so the FPS character in the camera, let's select the first
person character, actually, first of all, okay, and move it right there, then select the
first person camera, it is inside the ground, so move it up and let's move it forward like
this case, so the character is in the sky, let's now double click on it, we can move
the character right here, okay, then select the camera and move it right here, that is it,
often this, you can click on the game view, okay, so this is the environment, what we're
going to do with it, is we're going to click on player related, then open up the first
person camera controller, the camera pivot rotator, and then click on camera, and when
you click on it right here, there's type us and this post processing behavior script
will come up, select that and in here, make sure to select this post process florid
crowns, alright, and now as you can see the florid crowns effects are all applied to
the screen, okay, so if you want these effects, you can run that on, alright, now what we
can do is, we can actually go ahead and play the game now, and when you play the game
here we are, alright, everything looks good, there are the player feeds, alright, we can
punch, and if we change, we can show the flash light, there are these double guns and
that's it, either player can run, alright, we are unable to move on these stairs, don't
worry, we're going to fix that, but as you can see everything now works perfectly fine,
alright, but if you notice on the W button or the arrow button, the player keeps walking
and when we hold down the shift button, as you can see the player works, okay, so we're
going to fix all of these movement that according to our own liking, but for now everything
is set up, alright, and with this turn I'm going to just end this video right here.